Send them one by one?!
Yes. Sophia's orders.
She told us to send in the
transmogrified phantoms one by one.
What the hell is she thinking?
That's essentially begging for
them to be defeated individually.
In the end, she's only a scientist.
She doesn't know what a
real battle is all about!
Call her here immediately!
She went out to check the defense systems,
and she's not answering her
Sounding Stone either.
What?!
We're up against Thousand Tricks here!
We can take all the precautions we want,
but if the leader is incompetent,
we can even lose this easy fight!
Flick, even though our mentor said
that he gives her full authority,
winning is what is crucial here.
That's right.
At this rate, she will embarrass our mentor.
Let all the phantoms loose!
We'll crush them in one go!
Yes, sir!
Sophia Black.
I'll show you how to do battle.
So these are the guys who
made that slime-like thing...
It only took a single injection
to create such a monster, huh?
Let us get right to the point.
Your boss is the Master of Mages, correct?
My name is Sitri Smart.
We can guarantee your safety, so please
tell us where he can be found.
A-As if we'd tell you!
We'll happily give our lives for our mentor!
I knew it.
You're Noctus Cochlear's disciples.
I'll have you know that I've been
following the Akashic Tower for a long time.
I know about you as well.
I don't want to have to
use uncivilized measures.
Where is Noctus Cochlear?
I see.
Why don't I use this, then?
This potion should
loosen your tongue a bit.
Stop right there, Sitri Smart.
Isn't that an illegal potion?
It can muddle someone's consciousness,
force a confession, or erase memories.
It can also potentially be used
for brainwashing. It's very dangerous!
Don't tell me you concocted this yourself?
That's irrelevant. If we don't hurry,
Noctus Cochlear will get away.
This is for justice.
Easy, Adoria.
Sitri.
I understand where you're coming from,
but you can't just do whatever
you want to prisoners.
We're not criminals.
You, of all people, should
understand that the most.
Excuse me, sir.
It was a joke.
This really is just colored water.
See? Nothing happened.
I'm fine.
I mean, I do have a resistance
against colored water.
More importantly,
it seems we've run out of time.
"Perfect Play."
This isn't your ordinary water pistol.
It's a relic given to me
by someone important.
Episode 08
I Want to Rush In When It's Over
"I Want to Rush In When It's Over."
Let This Grieving Soul Retire
It's finally time!
This is the end for you all!
A bunch of useless hunters
standing in the way of progress.
Just die already!
You were right.
It wasn't just that one.
So now what do we do?
There are several types of magic
barrier that these phantoms can have.
We need to narrow down which element
works on which area in order to break it down.
You sound downright relaxed.
It's faster than the previous one!
The color's different, too.
This means its base is likely different.
Those with shields,
please take to the front line!
What?
This is necessary to determine the
force field's output and direction.
Please let go as soon as contact
is made with the shield.
Otherwise, it could rip off your arm!
Are you serious?
This really is just like he said.
Lyle!
Mages, please slow it down!
It's a revolving force field.
It turns clockwise.
Varies by body part?
If it blows you away with just one touch,
melee fighters don't have a chance.
So it would do that to my axe, too?
What are we going to do?
Wait until it runs out of magic?
No.
Considering its size and the
amount of mana material it has,
it could easily last another hour.
What a huge pain.
Now I see why Krai wanted to send Ark here.
If we concentrate all our magical attacks
on one spot and hit it multiple times,
or if we can temporarily nullify
part of the magic barrier,
we could get through.
But that would require
an extremely high level of skill.
And with this current crew...
The next one's coming!
There's more?!
Seriously, now?
Sitri, let's retreat.
Our people are exhausted.
We can't hold out any longer.
Running away won't be easy, either.
Even if we call in the mages for
reinforcement, it might be too late.
You're right.
I'm so done with this.
I never thought people this stupid
would be in the Akashic Tower.
What?
Mages, stop the magical attacks.
Everyone, step back.
What is going on?
It's just as I expected.
They probably attacked the hunters
in order to replenish their depleting
levels of mana material.
And the thing here with even more
mana material than the hunters is...
Now I get it.
Phantoms are masses of mana material.
The only word for this is "asinine."
Not sure if we're lucky or what.
I can't believe it!
The fruit of our great research...
The transmogrified phantoms
have such a weakness?!
Why...
didn't they just send them
in one after another?
I'm sick of your utter stupidity!
I told you to treat Sophia's
words as if they were my own.
To make matters worse,
you didn't realize your mistake
and used up all the
transmogrification potion!
P-Please forgive us.
We had no idea what had
happened on the battlefield.
Why did I choose not to send multiple
transmogrified phantoms at once?
If you think about it, it's obvious.
It's not that I lack experience in battle,
nor am I giving out random directives.
Flick, you simply lack
what we call "imagination."
Oh, well.
That was not the only weapon in our arsenal.
What is our next move, Sophia?
The situation has already changed.
Not only has Sitri Smart
joined the investigation party,
but a former level 7 hunter,
Gark Welter, has as well.
What?!
The Association's branch manager
has come to the front lines?
Though he is long retired, he is
unmistakably one of the true heroes.
Now that we have lost
the transmogrification potions,
our fight is going to be more difficult.
Sophia, why you...
Stop it, Flick.
You embarrass yourself.
F-Forgive me. I just...
So what do we do now?
Do we retreat?
No.
We cannot walk away from this empty-handed.
That would influence your standing
within the Akashic Tower as well.
Most importantly, our side
has had hostages taken.
We don't know when they'll talk
How dare you, Sophia?!
Those two are also seekers of truth who
have sworn their loyalty to our mentor!
They will reveal nothing!
I would also like for that to be true.
But even without those
two spilling anything,
Sitri Smart will eventually
find our headquarters.
Given that fact, it'll be a full-on battle
where we have to strike first to win.
Let us use the Malice
Eaters to overpower them.
We'll draw the survivors into our reach,
use our trump cards, and destroy them all.
If we kill them all,
there will be no one left to talk.
An interesting idea.
But the Malice Eaters are
still only partially trained.
For the best results, we'll need
someone to command them.
Flick, it's finally time for you to shine.
You're welcome to utilize
all of the creatures.
Please feel free to fully
unleash your power.
I truly cannot imagine a mage of your
skill failing to succeed if you do.
I know!
Sir, I promise that I will
teach those hunters a lesson!
Sitri Smart.
A rare breed amongst hunters.
An alchemist, just like me.
Fitting of her former second name, "The Prodigy,"
she was a person overflowing with
overwhelming talent and passion.
She was a born genius and a hard worker.
In order to get closer to the truth,
she was willing to conduct any experiment,
no matter how dangerous or difficult.
She never gave up, no matter
how daunting the situation,
doing everything she could
within the confines of the law.
She was so extraordinarily smart and pure
that I remember feeling
something akin to fear
and a tiny bit of jealousy next to her.
I could never become her.
Something on your mind?
Sven...
This afternoon was really intense.
I never would've guessed that the
anti-slime stuff wouldn't work.
I must have embarrassed you, too.
Oh, not at all.
The problem is that Krai always
leaves out vital information.
Like saying something is "slime-like"
when it's not a true slime at all.
He really needs to rein in
this Thousand Trials thing.
That's true.
So, I've been wondering this the entire time,
but why do they keep staring at you?
Um, I don't really know.
Maybe because your hair stands out?
Well, anyway, if anything happens,
let me know right away.
I will.
What...?
Don't push yourself too hard, Sitri.
Gark.
We may have mobilized a great many hunters,
but this is still just an investigation.
If we're up against the Akashic Tower,
this isn't something that the
Association can handle by itself.
Depending on their next moves,
we should avoid overextending
and pull back for a—
I have figured out the rough
location of the enemy.
What?
Well, anyway...
By considering the flow of the ley lines,
the concentration of mana material,
the difference in altitude
and geological features,
and where the slime-like things appeared,
this cliff here seems to be
a very likely place.
Such an in-depth analysis in such
a short time, all by yourself.
This is unbelievable.
Well, that's Sitri.
So, did I get it right,
disciples of Noctus Cochlear?
Th-That's pure conjecture,
and it's completely wrong!
Totally off! That's not even
remotely where it is!
Looks like I guessed correctly, then.
It would even be possible to attack before
Noctus Cochlear has a chance to escape.
If we've come this far,
we should give it a shot.
Yeah.
S-Stop it!
There's nothing there!
Our mentor isn't there!
We can't let them go over there!
Sophia, hurry and untie our restraints!
Sophia?
Who's that?
Who knows?
It must be one of their friends nearby.
That's right.
If she'd just come out already,
things would be easier.
Do you know her?
I do.
She's Noctus Cochlear's
disciple and my nemesis.
Sophia Black.
No matter how hard I look for her,
she is as elusive as a shadow.
If we don't apprehend Noctus and Sophia,
this kind of research will never end.
Simply put, those two together are
the vilest and most evil mages of them all.
As if Sophia would ever
lose to the likes of you!
She may be an infuriating
woman, but she's got skills!
A level 2 failure like you stands no chance!
It is my ineptitude that has allowed
her to evade capture until now.
But I will not lose.
I swear on my honor that I will slam
her into the South Isteria prison!
Sitri... you...
It doesn't bother me.
I am not blameless for that one case.
Krai, I love you!
I wanted to go even later,
showing up when basically
everything was already done.
Let's hurry up and go!
Get moving before Si dies!
She's not going to die.
If anyone's dying, it's me.
I couldn't charge any of my relics.
I don't have enough Safety Rings, either.
I'm in a pickle before we even start.
Master, we're coming up
on the White Wolf's Den.
What?
I can't see a thing.
Come on, let's go.
Master, it's dark and dangerous,
so I was thinking I could...
take your hand...
How dare you?!
It'll be a million light years before
you're worthy to hold his hand!
Save the dreams for bedtime!
Actually, shut up and go to sleep!
Liz.
Light years are a measure
of distance, not time.
Owl's Eye.
This should do the trick for now.
I don't know how long this
relic will hold up, though.
Just leave it to me, Krai!
No matter who or what comes
at us, I'll kill 'em dead!
You need to guard him, too!
Y-Yes!
Not that I know what a useless
shit like you could even do!
That reminds me.
Sitri said something about the entire
investigation party getting wiped out.
I wonder if they're okay...
I see. So Thousand Tricks isn't coming.
The level 8 that you and
Obsidian Cross look up to...
If only I had recognized
his greatness earlier,
I wouldn't have ended up like this.
Krai is basically someone who was
born to become a treasure hunter.
I'm sure he'll eventually get to level 10.
Level 10?!
Now I want to meet him even more.
He must be really strong.
He is.
But strength is just one of many factors.
Even if Krai was hypothetically weaker than
a sand rabbit in combat, it wouldn't matter.
A sand rabbit?
Bun bun?
I don't think I quite understand.
That's just how amazing he is.
Speaking of, Sitri.
You didn't bring that magical creature
you always have with you today?
Oh, if you mean Killiam, he's
undergoing maintenance right no—
See that?
That's my high-level magic attack,
Calamity Thunder!
You don't need that woman's defense
system as long as I'm around.
Looks like I used a bit too much mana,
but my spells kill in one hit, anyway.
Killing the entire investigation
party will make my mentor happy t—
You bastard...
So you're with the Akashic Tower!
I guess you hunters are tough.
I'll give you that much.
But it's over now.
I'll bury you, along with the humiliation
that woman inflicted upon me!
I can't believe it.
You used an area-of-effect
spell when we have hostages.
I kind of knew I was no replacement for Krai.
Y-You!
Didn't you get hit by my Calamity Thunder?
Let me reply with a question: why do you
think that spell would render me immobile?
Spells of that level aren't rare in the
high-level treasure vaults we frequent.
Lies!
You're saying my trump card—
that my Calamity Thunder...
is nothing special?
It means that you simply lack
what we call "imagination."
B-Branch Manager!
Sorry I took so long.
Those with healing spells, please get to it!
If any hearts stopped
beating, give them a kick!
Please hurry!
I can't believe Sitri shoots
pressurized potion to heal people.
Clever use of a water pistol.
That idiot!
Sophia told him to take
all the Malice Eaters!
Why did he only take one?!
Why can he not follow a single command?!
Does he still not see the
difference in ability?!
Even with Flick's Calamity Thunder,
the damage to their troop was minimal.
It seems they keep marching on.
Everything is running counter
to our expectations.
The transmogrified phantoms were
defeated, our location was easily deduced,
and not even Calamity Thunder was effective.
It's as if Thousand Tricks had engineered
everything to turn out like this.
Those insufferable hunters!
Sir, you at least need to escape.
We'll hold them off using
the remaining Malice Eaters.
Not yet.
We've still got an ace up our sleeves.
We have Akasha.
Not to mention, we still have Sophia.
We have no need to abandon this
place until we've completely lost.
Witnessing my disciples fight to the
bitter end is also my responsibility.
Master of Mages!
Sir!
In the name of the Akashic Tower,
destroy the investigation troop!
Go forth and win, my disciples!
Yes, sir!
Right, Sophia?
What a bother.
There's no doubt. Noctus Cochlear's
headquarters are further into this cave.
So get through them before
they get us first, huh?
Just like Krai, you're
asking for the impossible.
Not for the former "War Demon," it isn't.
Sven, Sitri, entrust your lives to me.
The three of us will go in first.
The mages will back us up.
First, we have to cut down the chimeras.
Then everyone enters to crush them!
I can't let this end with
Liz mocking me like that.
What is this?
Looks like traces of some
kinda lightning spell.
A pretty mediocre one, at that.
Given the scale of this thing,
I don't know if "mediocre" is the word...
The decisive battle is
finally drawing close.
What is Noctus Cochlear's
ultimate weapon, "Akasha"?!
What will Sophia Black's next move be?
And will our Krai Andrey continue
to not be part of any of this?!
Find out in the next episode!
Please tune in next time!
All right, everyone! Do your best!
By: Sitri Smart on stage
Come on, come on, everyone tough it out!
The final battle with Noctus Cochlear!
Go, go, boom, boom,
let's go!
This is it! The moment of truth!
The Akashic Tower still
has tricks up its sleeve!
The earth splits, and
something jet-black appears?!
Next time on Let This Grieving Soul Retire...
Episode 09
I Want to Teach Love and Peace
Okay, Krai, one for the road?
"I Want to Teach Love and Peace."